<?xml version ="1.0" encoding ="UTF-8" ?><data><location>181,122</location> <convo>Oh, PAT buses, why can't I quit you?\n\nHere's the deal: I 100% blame Pittsburgh's bus system problems on Port Authority.  Between the winding bus routes, the inability of buses to show up on time, and the outrageous money spent on retirement plans, it should be disbanded.  The city needs to take over and reconfigure the entire system.  The Post-Gazette has printed some great pieces that explain how the system could be overhauled.\n\nI've been a bus rider since birth (I still never drive), and it's only gotten worse over the years.  Some routes are great (outside of rush hours), others are ridiculous, and some good routes were recently cut.  Until transfers are free (which they should be within an hour window, in my opinion), it was insane to cut the 500, which added $10 a week to my bus tab just to get to work.\n\nIt is usable?  If you don't care about being on time.  I shouldn't have to show up 10 minutes early to catch a bus that should be coming by every 20 minutes according to the schedule.  I shouldn't have to stand in the middle of downtown traffic to flag down the 28x Airport Flyer when I'm standing at the stop and have an enormous purple suitcase.  When I'm going to work, I look up when I should be arriving...And then go back 1-2 time blocks to make sure I'm on time since I can't trust the bus.\n\nBus riders understand not all buses use the exclusive bus lanes, but maybe Port Authority should build the delays that happen every day into the schedule.  For example, there is not a chance that an inbound 71B takes a similar amount of time during the morning rush hour as it does mid-day.  I know this from experience.  Why doesn't the schedule know this?\n\nThe buses are so bad that now that I am two miles from work, I walk to and from every day.  In fact, I often BEAT the 71B home.  That means as I stroll two miles down Fifth Avenue, not a single bus passes me.  On the busiest section of the busiest non-highway street in Pittsburgh (data according to me).  How is this possible?\n\nFinally, we live in Pittsburgh.  It's cold or raining or miserable most of the year.  I would gladly take fewer stops in exchange for heated bus shelters.  It would also be nice if these imaginary shelters could have bus arrival information.  Pitt's on the right track with their bus shelters at the Cathedral--take note.</convo> <class></class></data>