<?xml version ="1.0" encoding ="UTF-8" ?><data><location>222,212</location> <convo>While I have always had a great experience with my food, I feel the need to update my prior review based on my experience at brunch today.  \n\nWhen my food came out, there was a very visible hair on my plate. I was with a large group and did not want to make a scene, so I mentioned it to the server who immediately took my plate away. The manager on duty came out to apologize, which I did appreciate. However, I was a little surprised because when they brought my plate out about 5 minutes later, I could tell that it was the same exact plate. \n\nFirst off, it was not even warm, so if they made my meal on the spot you would think it would be hot, or at the very least warm. I had also substituted bacon for the sausage that normally comes with the entree, and if the chef had made a new plate on the spot, he would probably have sent it out with the sausage (or with a side of bacon again), which he did not (they had served my bacon on the side when they brought it out initially).     Everything was in the exact same place on the plate. I wasn't going to cause a scene, so I pretended to enjoy it, but did not. I was quite repulsed.\n\nin my last review I had said that Casbah was my favorite restaurant in Pittsburgh. I had mentioned that the Cassericia dish was my favorite but that they had removed it from the menu the last time I tried to order it there for dinner. I received a response from someone at the restaurant that she was not sure why I would think that because it is still offered, and I explained that the waiter told me it was removed from the menu. \n\nI'm not really sure what happened here, but I can tell you this... I don't think that Casbah is my favorite anymore. In fact not only is it not my favorite, it has taken a plunge to the bottom of my list of places to eat. \n\nFor me, if you expect to eat at a top restaurant, the service should be top of the line, and it has just been too inconsistent for my taste. No thanks Casbah!</convo> <class></class></data>