<?xml version ="1.0" encoding ="UTF-8" ?><data><location>148,66</location> <convo>FINDLAY, Ohio--(BUSINESS WIRE)--Apr 24, 2018--Quiet, comfortable and fast, the new Mastercraft Avenger M8™ is rolling onto the ultra high performance market as a W-rated tire that’s designed to make everyday driving fun. The Avenger M8 offers all season traction, soft handling and a 40,000-mile treadwear warranty.
This press release features multimedia. View the full release here: https://www.businesswire.com/news/home/20180424005909/en/
Cooper Tire's new Mastercraft Avenger M8™ is an ultra high performance tire offering comfort and quiet as well as a 40,000-mile treadwear warranty. (Photo: Business Wire)
“Whether trekking across the country or cruising around town, your ride should be as smooth as possible. That’s why Mastercraft is debuting its most comfortable ultra high performance tire yet – the Avenger M8,” said Scott Jamieson, Cooper’s Director of Product Management for North America. “Featuring a noise-sealing tread design and enhanced elastic base layering, the new Avenger M8 provides drivers with the precise handling and stability needed for a smooth and quiet riding experience in wet or dry weather.”
In addition to the noise sealing ribs and enhanced base tread layer, the tire features a broad tread width and wide center rib which provide substantial ground contact for great stability and responsiveness. There are seven circumferential grooves in the Avenger M8 allowing for faster water drainage to guard against hydroplaning.
The Mastercraft Avenger M8 is available in 19 popular sizes, from 16- to 19-inch rim diameters.
About Cooper Tire &amp; Rubber Company
Cooper Tire &amp; Rubber Company (NYSE: CTB) is the parent company of a global family of companies that specializes in the design, manufacture, marketing and sale of passenger car, light truck, medium truck, motorcycle and racing tires. Cooper’s headquarters is in Findlay, Ohio, with manufacturing, sales, distribution, technical and design operations within its family of companies located in more than one dozen countries around the world. For more information on Cooper, visit www.coopertire.com, www.facebook.com/coopertire or www.twitter.com/coopertire.
View source version on businesswire.com:https://www.businesswire.com/news/home/20180424005909/en/
CONTACT: Cooper Tire &amp; Rubber Company
Megan James, 419-424-4251
majames@coopertire.com
KEYWORD: UNITED STATES NORTH AMERICA OHIO
INDUSTRY KEYWORD: MANUFACTURING CHEMICALS/PLASTICS AUTOMOTIVE AFTERMARKET MOTORCYCLES OFF-ROAD TRUCKS &amp; SUVS RECREATIONAL VEHICLES TIRES &amp; RUBBER GENERAL AUTOMOTIVE
SOURCE: Cooper Tire &amp; Rubber Company
Copyright Business Wire 2018.
PUB: 04/24/2018 09:30 AM/DISC: 04/24/2018 09:30 AM
http://www.businesswire.com/news/home/20180424005909/en</convo> <class>official</class></data>