<?xml version ="1.0" encoding ="UTF-8" ?><data><location>236,190</location> <convo>MELCROFT, Pa. (AP) — In a story Jan. 28 about the shooting deaths of four people at a car wash, The Associated Press, relying on information from state police, misspelled the first name of one of the female victims. She was Cortney Snyder, not Courtney.
A corrected version of the story is below:
The Latest: Victims' family says suspect driven by jealousy
Family members of the victims of a shooting at a Pennsylvania car wash say the suspect was driven by jealousy
MELCROFT, Pa. (AP) — The Latest on a fatal shooting outside a Pennsylvania car wash (all times local):
6:45 p.m.
Family members of the victims of a shooting at a Pennsylvania car wash say the suspect was driven by jealousy.
State police say 28-year-old Timothy Smith fatally shot four people at Ed's Car Wash around 3 a.m. in Saltlick Township, a rural town about 55 miles (89 kilometers) southeast of Pittsburgh.
Twenty-seven-year-old William Porterfield, 25-year-old Chelsie Cline, 23-year-old Cortney Snyder and 21-year-old Seth Cline were all killed.
Smith is on life support and not expected to survive after suffering a gunshot wound to his head. State police say it's possible the gunshot wound was self-inflicted.
Authorities would not immediately say how Smith knew the victims but family members tell the Pittsburgh Tribune-Review that Smith had developed an obsession with Chelsie Cline.
____
4:45 p.m.
State police say a man suspected of fatally shooting four people at a car wash in Pennsylvania is on life support.
Authorities initially had said that five people had died in the shootings early Sunday in the Melcroft community of Saltlick Township, about 55 miles (89 kilometers) southeast of Pittsburgh. Another person was injured.
But state police now say the suspect, Tim Smith, is on life support at a hospital.
Authorities have identified the four people killed as 27-year-old William Porterfield, 25-year-old Chelsie Cline, 23-year-old Cortney Snyder and 21-year-old Seth Cline.
Authorities say a woman who was injured survived by hiding in the back seat of a truck.
A motive for the shooting remains under investigation.
____
2:15 p.m.
Family members say a domestic dispute spurred the shooting deaths of five people at a Pennsylvania car wash.
But state police say they haven't yet confirmed that or a motive for the shootings that occurred early Sunday in the Melcroft community of Saltlick Township, about 55 miles (89 kilometers) southeast of Pittsburgh. WPXI-TV reports they spoke with family members.
The victims were identified only as three men and two women in their 20s and 30s. Four of the victims were pronounced dead at the scene. Another died at a hospital.
An injured person was hospitalized. His or her condition and identity is not yet known.
The Pittsburgh Tribune-Review reports a man who lives near the scene said he heard about 30 gunshots over a span of several minutes.
___
This story has been corrected to show that the TV station is WPXI-TV, not WXPI-TV.
___
12:20 p.m.
State police say three men and two women have been found dead in a shooting at a Pennsylvania car wash.
The shooting occurred shortly before 3 a.m. Sunday in the Melcroft community of Saltlick Township, about 55 miles (89 kilometers) southeast of Pittsburgh.
Police said Sunday they have no motive yet for the deadly shooting. Four of the victims were pronounced dead at the scene, while another died at a hospital.
Two victims died inside a vehicle and two were found outside in the car wash's parking lot.
An injured person was taken to a hospital. Authorities say it's not clear if that person was shot. Details on that person's condition were not immediately released.
Authorities were trying to determine if the shooter was among those found at the scene.
___
10:20 a.m.
State police say at least five people were killed in a shooting at a Pennsylvania car wash.
WPXI-TV reports the shooting occurred around 2:45 a.m. Sunday in Melcroft.
Melcroft is about 55 miles (89 kilometers) southeast of Pittsburgh
The victims were identified only as three men and two women. At least one other person was wounded and was taken to a hospital, but further details on that person's condition were not immediately released.
Authorities were trying to determine if the shooter was among those found at the scene.
A motive for the shooting remains under investigation.</convo> <class>official</class></data>