<?xml version ="1.0" encoding ="UTF-8" ?><data><location>236,132</location> <convo>BOSTON--(BUSINESS WIRE)--May 30, 2018--The global smart home market ended on an upbeat note in 2017 reaching $84 billion, up 16% from $72 billion in 2016 according to a report just released by. According to the report, “”, worldwide consumer spending on smart home devices, systems and services will total nearly $96 billion in 2018 and grow at 10% CAGR over the forecast period (2018 to 2023) to $155 billion. North America will account for 41% of total spending or $40 billion, followed by the Asia-Pacific region at $26 billion and Western Europe at $17 billion.
This press release features multimedia. View the full release here: https://www.businesswire.com/news/home/20180530006126/en/
Households with "Smart" Systems: Global Total (Graphic: Strategy Analytics)
New offerings from big brand tech firms such as Amazon, Google (Nest), ADT and Samsung are driving adoption in North America. In Europe, UK-based Centrica Connected Homes’ Hive along with Deutsche Telekom’s Magenta Home, Germany’s eQ-3 and the Netherlands Enco’s Toon are stimulating market demand. In Asia-Pacific, China’s Xiaomi, Korean service provider LG U+, Japan’s iTSCOM and Panasonic, as well as, Origin and Telstra in Australia are powering the market.
“The market continues to mature,” stated Bill Ablondi, Director of Strategy Analytics’ Smart Home Strategies advisory service. “Consumer awareness is rising, prices are coming down, and the technology is becoming more intuitive. Yet, there is still a high degree of fragmentation, with numerous firms competing for smart home consumers. Who will ultimately succeed in capturing growth in this market remains unclear.”
About Strategy Analytics
Strategy Analytics, Inc. provides the competitive edge with advisory services, consulting and actionable market intelligence for emerging technology, mobile and wireless, digital consumer and automotive electronics companies. With offices in North America, Europe and Asia, Strategy Analytics delivers insights for enterprise success.
View source version on businesswire.com:https://www.businesswire.com/news/home/20180530006126/en/
CONTACT: Strategy Analytics, Inc.
Bill Ablondi, +1 617-614-0744
wablondi@strategyanalytics.com
or
Jack Narcotta, +1 617-614-0798
jnarcotta@strategyanalytics.com
KEYWORD: UNITED STATES NORTH AMERICA MASSACHUSETTS
INDUSTRY KEYWORD: TECHNOLOGY CONSUMER ELECTRONICS HARDWARE INTERNET AUDIO/VIDEO SECURITY MOBILE/WIRELESS
SOURCE: Strategy Analytics, Inc.
Copyright Business Wire 2018.
PUB: 05/30/2018 12:52 PM/DISC: 05/30/2018 12:52 PM
http://www.businesswire.com/news/home/20180530006126/en</convo> <class>official</class></data>