<?xml version ="1.0" encoding ="UTF-8" ?><data><location>215,243</location> <convo>All Times Eastern
NASCAR
COKE ZERO SUGAR 400
Site: Daytona Beach, Florida.
Schedule: Thursday, practice, 2:05 &amp; 4:05 p.m. (NBCSN); Friday, qualifying, 4:10 p.m. (NBCSN); Saturday, race, 7 p.m., NBCSN.
Track: Daytona International Speedway (oval, 2.5 miles).
Race distance: 400 miles, 160 laps.
Last year: Ricky Stenhouse Jr. won after starting sixth.
Last race: Kyle Busch took the checkered flag at Chicagoland for the fifth time in 2018.
Fast facts: Busch and Kevin Harvick each have five wins in their first 17 starts of the season. That's only happened one other time since 1977, as Denny Hamlin and Jimmie Johnson had five victories by this point in the season in 2010. ...The last six races at Daytona have been determined by less than a half-second, and a 2007 race was the third closest since the inception of electronic scoring and timing. Jamie McMurray beat Kyle Busch by 0.005 seconds 11 years ago. ... William Byron leads Bubba Wallace by 37 points in the rookie of the year standings.
Next race: Quaker State 400, July 14, Kentucky Speedway, Sparta, Kentucky.
Online: http://www.nascar.com
___
XFINITY
COCA-COLA FIRECRACKER 250
Site: Daytona Beach, Florida
Schedule: Thursday, practice, 1:05 &amp; 3:05 p.m. (NBCSN); Friday, qualifying, 2:10 p.m. (NBCSN), race, 7:30 p.m., NBCSN.
Track: Daytona International Speedway.
Race distance: 250 miles, 100 laps.
Last year: William Byron won at Daytona, his second straight victory.
Last race: Kyle Larson won at Chicagoland from the pole.
Fast facts: The last six series races at Daytona have produced six different winners. ...JR Motorsports has taken first in five of the last nine events at the track, including Tyler Reddick earlier this season. ...Cole Custer is atop the series standings for the first time in his career. Custer is three points ahead of Daniel Hemric and four points better than Elliott Sadler. ...Justin Haley will make his series debut in the No. 23 Chevrolet for GMS Racing.
Next race: Alsco 300, July 13, Kentucky Speedway.
Online: http://www.nascar.com
___
CAMPING WORLD TRUCK
Last race: Brett Moffitt won for the second time in three starts at Chicagoland.
Next race: Buckle Up in Your Truck 225, July 12, Kentucky Speedway.
Online: http://www.nascar.com
___
VERIZON INDYCAR
IOWA CORN 300
Site: Newton, Iowa
Schedule: Saturday, practice, 11:15 a.m., qualifying, 3:30 p.m. (NBCSN), practice, 6:45 p.m.; Sunday, race, 2 p.m., NBCSN.
Track: Iowa Speedway (oval, 0.894 miles)
Race distance: 268.2 miles, 300 laps.
Last year: Former series star Helio Castroneves took first at Iowa.
Last race: Josef Newgarden won for the third time in 2018 at Road America.
Fast facts: Iowa will be the fourth oval race of the season. Newgarden (Phoenix), Will Power (Indianapolis) and Scott Dixon (Texas) won the first three. ... . Ryan Hunter-Reay is the only active driver to take first at Iowa more than once. He won in 2012, 2014 and 2015. ... No pole sitter has won in Newton in 11 tries. ... Matheus Leist took the Indy Lights race at Iowa in 2017 after starting 10th.
Next race: Honda Indy Toronto, July 15, Streets of Toronto, Toronto.
Online: http://www.indycar.com
___
FORMULA ONE
BRITISH GRAND PRIX
Site: Silverstone, England
Schedule: Friday, practice, 5 &amp; 9 a.m.; Saturday, practice, 6 a.m., qualifying, 9 a.m.; Sunday, race, 9:10 a.m.
Track: Silverstone Circuit (3.66 miles).
Race distance: 190.3 miles, 52 laps.
Last year: Lewis Hamilton won from the pole on his home track.
Last race: Max Verstappen won his first race of the season in Austria.
Fast facts: Hamilton, Valterri Bottas and Daniel Ricciardo were among six drivers whose races ended early last week. Those issues helped shake up the standings, with Sebastian Vettel vaulting over Hamilton for first place. But Vettel's lead is by just one point (146-145). ... McLaren racing director Eric Boullier resigned this week after the team notched just four points in the last four races.
Next race: German Grand Prix, July 22, Hockenheimring, Hockenheim, Germany.
Online: http://www.formula1.com
___
NHRA MELLO YELLO DRAG RACING
NEW ENGLAND NATIONALS
Site: Epping, New Hampshire.
Schedule: Friday, qualifying, 5 &amp; 7:30 p.m.; Saturday, qualifying, 2 &amp; 4:30 p.m.; Sunday, finals, 3:37 p.m.
Track: New England Dragway
Last year: Brittany Force won in New Hampshire in early June 2017.
Last race: Blake Alexander claimed his first career win in Top Fuel in Ohio.
Fast facts: Alexander qualified 12th and beat Antron Brown, Tony Schumacher and Leah Pritchett before entering his second career final round, where he took down Terry McMillen. ... Matt Hagan (Funny Car), Tanner Gray (Pro Stock) and Eddie Krawiec (Pro Stock Motorcycle) also claimed victories in Norwalk two weeks ago. It was the second win of the season for Hagan, a two-time world champion.
Next race: Mile High Nationals, July 20-22, Bandimere Speedway, Morrison, Colorado.
Online: http://www.nhra.com
___
OTHER RACES
WORLD OF OUTLAWS: Friday &amp; Saturday; FVP Platinum Battery Showdown, Cedar Lake Speedway, New Richmond, Wisconsin.
Online: http://www.woosprint.com</convo> <class>official</class></data>