<?xml version ="1.0" encoding ="UTF-8" ?><data><location>278,120</location> <convo>terrible... terrible terrible terrible... funny, the food there reminded me of the end of Goodfellas where the guy ordered pasta in a restaurant and got watery noodles and ketchup... yeah, not too far off the mark here. \n\nlet me back up a bit first.... My stepson and I were on our own for dinner so made sense to go out for the evening. So I picked this place knowing it was a kid friendly joint and not chili's or fuddruckers etc. The building itself is great. I loved the feeling of going into this renovated looking warehouse. He thought it was cool as well. The best part was inside. the decor is fantastic, and really the only reason to go. Loads of vintage signs and things and smack in the middle of the one dining room - a real vintage trolly car - completely renovated... of course I asked for us to be seated inside there... that was really neat. \n\nThen the food came... I had spaghetti and Meatballs and a Caesar salad. Now, the salad was really flavorful and fresh. Normally I hate salads in places like this. the lettuce tastes old and rubbery... not in this case. it was excellent. The spaghetti on the other hand - wow, watery, slightly overcooked noodles and sauce I bet was straight out of a Hunt's Spaghetti sauce can. the meatballs were frozen and reheated - i hate that off taste frozen meat takes on. so the salad got an A and spaghetti was a bit loser. \n\nMy stepson ordered the Italian wedding soup - he loved it - I did not try it... he also got the same watery noodles with the mushroom red sauce. Those mushrooms must have come straight from a can. they were button and the one I tasted had that tinned flavor.... so essentially this restaurant depends completely on frozen, processed, canned ingredients rather than fresh and flavorful. \n\nBottom line... have kids with you? they will love it... just the adults? find something... anything else... it is going to disappoint.</convo> <class></class></data>