<?xml version ="1.0" encoding ="UTF-8" ?><data><location>162,87</location> <convo>Went here last night to meet folks for a friend's birthday party. Docking one star due to a few unfortunate things that happened, otherwise I'd be fine giving this place a 3.\n\nOur waiter was very attentive and kept our water and soda cups refilled, the food was decent overall - I had a plain ol' burger and a delicious berry sangria - and the place overall had a nice vibe to it and was pretty comfortable and fun to be in...you'd think this would just be another average place not-great-but-not-bad and I'd be ready to go on to the next review right there.\n\nHere's where I ran into problems. I'd checked the website in advance to try and plan my meal since I do my best to pick items on menus that aren't, say, 2,000 calories in one sitting. Their website advertises that they make skinny drinks; when I asked my waiter he said it was possible but that they did not normally do this and that it's a hassle for the people at the bar, so he didn't recommend it. Then why tell us on your website that you'll do it??? \n\nAdditionally, while we had checked in advance when we made our reservation about bringing a birthday cake and the restaurant's ability to handle us lighting candles, apparently there was a break down in communication; we never got the candles we had asked for, and in fact the poor waiter struggled to even find a lighter before realizing there were no candles available. Obviously whatever error occurred wasn't the waiter's fault, and we definitely thanked him and tipped him well for doing the best that he could with what he had.\n \nOn a final note, this is also one of those places where if you ask for a medium rare burger, they will overcook it; I've started ordering medium rare on purpose specifically so that I get a medium cooked burger instead of medium well or well done.\n\nFinal verdict: go for the brews if you must, and the food's nice enough. I was admittedly left a little underwhelmed.</convo> <class></class></data>